<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on anuj says</title>
    <link>https://bearsonmars.github.io/tags/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on anuj says</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>© Anuj Kumar</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:41:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bearsonmars.github.io/tags/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Effective_communication</title>
      <link>https://bearsonmars.github.io/posts/effective_communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bearsonmars.github.io/posts/effective_communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How to get the intended message across as efficiently and as unambiguously as&#xA;possible in the shortest amount of time - is a question many of us might have&#xA;asked ourself at one point. I wish I knew the right answer. But, in the spirit&#xA;of enquiry, I shall endeavour to find a half decent answer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Economics Explains the World - by Andrew Leigh</title>
      <link>https://bearsonmars.github.io/bookshelf/economics_leigh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 22:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bearsonmars.github.io/bookshelf/economics_leigh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;thoughts-on-agriculture-and-building-heights&#34;&gt;Thoughts on Agriculture and Building heights&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Leigh says that Indus valley civilisation was among the firsts to adopt agriculture, grid patterned cities, ideal brick sizes, flushed toilets, toys, wheel etc. And the buildings were mostly of equal sizes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now does that mean that Indus Valley was a more &amp;ldquo;equal&amp;rdquo; civilisation compared to let&amp;rsquo;s say the Ancient Egyptian civilisation, with its vanity projects such as the Pyramids? Could the argument be further stretched to include our contemporary societies with a limited number of skyscrapers concentrated in downtown of a particular city? Is there any city on this planet in 21st century with similar sized buildings all over? Singapore, perhaps? Not sure, really. If there is, it probably is more equal. Why would residents accept public funds to be spent on some structure which most of them would not see the insides of in their lifetimes?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peak Human - by Johan Norberg</title>
      <link>https://bearsonmars.github.io/bookshelf/peak_human/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 11:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bearsonmars.github.io/bookshelf/peak_human/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the notes I made while reading this fascinating book. Absolutely recommed it to someone who wishes to understand how golden ages begin, and how they end - and they all DO end eventually!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dutch-republic&#34;&gt;The Dutch Republic&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The discovery of new continents and sea routes shook European consciousness and sparked a new wave of curiosity and knowledge building&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;renaissance-italy&#34;&gt;Renaissance Italy&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
